Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Additions Since 1978, 1926-1994; Series VII; 29.92; (34 boxes)
  - December 1994 Acquisition, 23.25' (25 boxes)
    - 1991 zoning hearing, 1991 March (Box 105)
    - Leff, Jonathan, 1991, undated (Box 105)
    - Vinh, Alphonse, 1992 (Box 105)
    - "Tennessee Squires", 1975-1981 (Box 105)
    - "Contemporary Authors", 1991 (Box 105)
    - "Current Aug. 1989" (Box 105)
    - Boult, Reber, 1979, undated (Box 105)
    - "Letters June 1989", 1985-1989 (Box 105)
    - "Letters of March 1990", 1989-1992 (Box 105)
    - Articles on Brooks and correspondence, 1983-1992, undated; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Indra, C. T. thesis, "The Literary Criticism of Cleanth Brooks", 1975 June (Box 105)
    - Understanding Fiction, 1986 (Box 105)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1987-1992, undated; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Anglican and Episcopalian correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 105)
    - "Diocese of Christ the King", 1983-1984, undated (Box 105)
    - "Prayer Book So. Current 1982", 1984, undated (Box 105)
    - "Anglican Affairs", 1971-1986 (Box 105)
    - Articles on religion, 1982-1985 (Box 105)
    - Unidentified Carroll manuscript, undated; 4 folders (Box 106)
    - Correspondence relating to the death of Cleanth Brooks, 1994 (Box 106)
    - Beecher and Bennett Funeral Service, undated (Box 106)
    - Publishing correspondence, 1986-1994 (Box 106)
    - Printed ephemera, 1921 (Box 106)
    - Publishing agreement, 1994 April (Box 106)
    - "Brooks Geneology", 1984, undated (Box 106)
    - "Misc. Letters, Commendatory", 1965-1985 (Box 106)
    - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 106)
    - "LSU Faulkner Book", undated (Box 106)
    - Unsorted writings, undated (Box 106)
    - "Pages in L. E. C. G. Retyped", undated (Box 106)
    - "Copies for Dick Lewis", 1937, 1985 (Box 106)
    - Awards, undated (Box 106)
    - Material relating to Flannery O'Connor, 1988, undated (Box 106)
    - Tassin, Anthony, 1984-1992 (Box 106)
    - "Beverly Jarrett & U. of Missouri Press", 1989-1992 (Box 106)
    - Rubin, Louis, 1987-1992, undated (Box 106)
    - Riley, Dr. "Pete", 1988-1992 (Box 106)
    - Jackson, Peter, 1989-1991 (Box 106)
    - Grimshaw, James A., 1987-1991 (Box 106)
    - "Correspondence, February 1990", 1989-1990 (Box 106)
    - Clark, William Bedford, 1988-1989 (Box 106)
    - Cox, James, undated (Box 106)
    - "Johnson on Science", undated (Box 106)
    - "[Harold] Bloom file", 1984-1985 (Box 106)
    - "James Cox and George Core", undated (Box 106)
    - Wigington, Nan, 1979-1984, undated (Box 106)
    - Clippings on education, 1943-1984, undated (Box 106)
    - "Donoghee's Essay on My Criticism & Frederick Conner...", undated (Box 106)
    - "Structuralism (Notes for Brick Lectures)", 1972-1982, undated (Box 106)
    - "Xmas Cards 1987" (Box 107)
    - Montgomery, Marion, 1993 (Box 107)
    - "Charlotte Beck on Fish and on Me", 1993, undated (Box 107)
    - Unsorted material, 1990-1993, undated; 3 folders (Box 107)
    - "Goebal Etc.", 1990-1993, undated; 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Winchell, Mark Royden, undated; 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Historical Evidence and the Reading of 17th-C Poetry, undated; 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Writings, drafts and printed versions, 1984-1991, undated (Box 107)
    - Correspondence, 1986, undated (Box 107)
    - Kimball, Roger, 1991, undated (Box 107)
    - "Reference Letter for Michael Babin", 1992 March 2 (Box 107)
    - Vinh, Alphonse, 1992 March 23 (Box 107)
    - Writings of others, 1989-1992, undated (Box 107)
    - Williams, Joan, 1989-1990, undated (Box 107)
    - Grimshaw, J.A., Jr., 1989 November 16 (Box 107)
      Contains envelope only
    - "Recent photographs", 1983 (Box 108)
    - "Blue Cross Notices" (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
    - "Quarterly Payments on 1988 Income Tax" (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
    - Brooker, Jewel Spears, 1937-1992; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - "Yale Press 1987", 1987-1988 (Box 108)
    - "Warren's Death Letters", 1989 (Box 108)
    - "Episcopal Church Amer. Scholar," notebook, undated (Box 108)
    - American Academy & Institute of Arts & Letters material, 1984-1988 (Box 108)
    - The Athenaeum material, 1984-1992; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - "[Notes?] for Alumni Lectures", 1987, undated (Box 108)
    - Oxford & Exeter College material, 1983-1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - St. George Tucker Society, 1991-1992, undated; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Material relating to Robert Frost, 1988 (Box 108)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1988-1994; 5 folders (Box 108)
    - "Make It the [Orate?]?", 1990, undated (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1988-1994, undated; 3 folders (Box 108)
    - " Historical Evidence, Notes & Papers", 1990-1991 (Box 108)
    - "Indra material", 1993, undated (Box 108)
    - "Joseph Carroll Book", undated (Box 108)
    - Blotner, Joseph, 1993 August 27 (Box 109)
    - Brown, Larry, Joe, proof, 1991; 2 folders (Box 109)
    - "The McTyeire School", 1920-1993, undated (Box 109)
    - Indra, C. T., 1981-1992, undated; 6 folders (Box 109)
      Includes copy of "Cleanth Brooks: A Human Poetics"
    - Miscellaneous material, 1993-1994, undated; 2 folders (Box 109)
    - L.S.U. Creative Writing program material, 1994, undated (Box 109)
    - Koppelman, Robert, 1994 (Box 109)
    - Printed material, 1979-1994; 9 folders (Box 109)
    - Printed material, 1990-1994; 8 folders (Box 110)
    - Grimshaw, James A., 1994 (Box 110)
    - "Personal Bibliography", 1985 (Box 110)
    - "Lectures for Bibliography", undated (Box 110)
    - Clippings, 1966-1971 (Box 110)
    - "Miscellaneous", 1984-1993 (Box 110)
    - "Jefferson Lecture Reviews", 1968-1985 (Box 110)
    - Unsorted ccorrespondence, 1959-1994, undated (Box 110)
    - Manuscript notes on Faulkner, 1979, undated; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - "Problems", 1992-1993 (Box 110)
    - Nebolsine, Arcadi, 1993, undated (Box 110)
    - "The American Dream," draft, typescript and notes, manuscript, undated (Box 110)
    - "My First Meeting With Robert Graves", undated (Box 110)
    - "Lamar Lecture I", undated (Box 110)
    - "For JMW", 1985-1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - " First Encounters (2nd Batch)", 1973-1984, undated (Box 110)
    - "Reviews of Mercer Lectures, Later, August 1987", 1986, undated (Box 110)
    - Bibliography of the writings of Cleanth Brooks, undated (Box 110)
    - "Materials for Jefferson Lecture", 1984-1985, undated; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - "Hollins Talk," draft, autograph manuscript, 1985 (Box 110)
    - On the Prejudices, Predilections, and Firm Beliefs of William Faulkner, proof, 1987 (Box 110)
      Includes photographs
    - "Notes for Lecture on Absalom ", undated (Box 110)
    - "Warren Beinecke Conference", 1987 (Box 110)
    - "Warren Lecture, July 14th Version", undated (Box 110)
    - "Faulkner: Master of the Heroic and the Pastoral Modes, Early Draft", 1987, undated (Box 110)
    - "Yale Archives", undated (Box 110)
    - Correspondence, 1987, undated (Box 110)
    - "Archives Correspondence, Misc. & Unsorted", 1986-1987 (Box 111)
    - "Warren Lecture, Various Drafts", undated (Box 111)
    - "R.P. Warren lecture August 1987", undated (Box 111)
    - "Warren A: Version", undated (Box 111)
    - "Oxford F. Conference 1987", 1987-1988, undated (Box 111)
    - "The Lamar Lectures (1984) at Mercer Univ.", undated (Box 111)
    - Clippings and notes, 1986 November (Box 111)
    - "Letters for Archives", 1984-1987 (Box 111)
    - "'Faulkner's World', Paper & Notes", 1987 (Box 111)
    - "Nicholls State, Thibodaux April 3, 1987, Archival", 1985-1987 (Box 111)
    - The New York Times Magazine, printed issue, 1990 July 29 (Box 111)
    - Untitled manuscript, undated (Box 111)
    - Clipping, 1984 November 26 (Box 111)
    - "Xeroxed Letters to Friends" (empty folder), undated (Box 111)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1991 (Box 111)
    - Clippings and notes, undated (Box 111)
    - Writings of others, 1989, undated (Box 111)
    - "Why Does Sherlock Holmes Endure?" draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 111)
    - "St. Louis Conference on Eliot," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 111)
    - "Boston Partisan Review", 1991, undated (Box 111)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1990-1991, undated (Box 111)
    - "Ham Jones, Ante-Bellum Southern Humorist," galley proof, 1989 (Box 111)
    - "North Carolina November 3, 1989 Paper...", undated (Box 111)
    - Professional correspondence, 1989-1991, undated; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - "Faulkner's Reputation as a Novelist," draft, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 111)
    - "Wasteland: 60 Yrs After", 1987-1988, undated (Box 111)
    - Conference material, 1988-1990, undated; 3 folders (Box 111)
    - Research material, undated (Box 111)
    - Rubin, Louis D., "The Mockingbird in the Gum Tree," proofs, 1991 October 18 (Box 111)
    - The Boston Globe Magazine, printed issue, 1991 October 27 (Box 111)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1973-1987; 4 folders (Box 111)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1968-1989; 11 folders (Box 112)
    - "My Grad. Seminar Lectures on the Romantic Poets", undated (Box 112)
    - "Lectures: Miscellaneous", 1969-1976, undated; 2 folders (Box 112)
    - "Frost and Nature, Frost Conference, Winthrop College 8-9 May 1980", undated (Box 112)
    - "Drafts of 2 1969 Essays by C.B.", undated (Box 112)
    - Hargrove, Nancy, undated (Box 112)
    - "My Lectures for the Romantic Seminar", undated; 4 folders (Box 112)
    - Brodsky, Louis Daniel, 1988 (Box 113)
    - Anthæum, The, 1984-1987 (Box 113)
    - Vanderbilt, undated (Box 113)
    - Yale, 1984, undated (Box 113)
    - SSSL, 1981-1988, undated (Box 113)
    - Foundation for Anglican Tradition, 1987-1988, undated (Box 113)
    - International Association of University Professors of English, 1984-1989 (Box 113)
    - Manuscript, 1981, 1984-1989 (Box 113)
    - "Encyclopedia of Southern Culture", 1984-1985 (Box 113)
    - "Oxford House Tuscaloosa", 1983 (Box 113)
    - "International Council for the Apostolic Faith", 1987 April 23 (Box 113)
    - "Guild of Scholars", 1981-1988, undated (Box 113)
    - "Yale Correspondence", 1981 October 12 (Box 113)
    - "Graduate Club", 1983-1989, undated (Box 113)
    - "Council of Scholars", 1984-1987 (Box 113)
    - "Oxford & Exeter College", 1989 (Box 113)
    - "American Academy of Arts and Sciences", 1985-1988, undated (Box 113)
    - "Royal Society of Literature", 1984-1989, undated (Box 113)
    - "National Humanities Center", 1981-1989 (Box 113)
    - "Friends of Friendless Churches", 1981, undated (Box 113)
    - "Library of Congress", 1984-1986, undated (Box 113)
    - "National Institute - Academy of Arts & Letters", 1985-1988 (Box 113)
    - "American Philosophical Society", 1983-1988; 2 folders (Box 113)
    - The Foundation for Anglican Tradition and related materials, 1984-1987, undated; 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1986, undated (Box 113)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences material, 1985-1987 (Box 113)
    - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 114)
    - "The Value of the Humanities", undated (Box 114)
    - Articles and manuscripts on criticism, 1990, undated (Box 114)
    - "Robert Penn Warren and the 'New Criticism'," lecture, 1990 (Box 114)
    - Introduction to Faulkner, undated (Box 114)
    - Unidentified writings, undated (Box 114)
    - Lecture notes, undated (Box 114)
    - "Faulkner's Reputation as a Novelist", undated (Box 114)
    - "Faulkner In the 'Thirties", undated (Box 114)
    - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 114)
    - "Videotapes on Faulkner for Buccoli Clark Layman", 1987 (Box 114)
    - "Intro to Faulkner's World", undated (Box 114)
    - "Notes on As I Lay Dying ", 1988, undated (Box 114)
    - The American Dream, undated (Box 114)
    - "Richard Wilbur Essay", 1993, undated (Box 114)
    - "Review of Geoffrey Hill's The Enemy's Country (1991)", 1991, undated (Box 114)
    - Yale Summer Lecture Series - A Sherlock Holmes Evening, undated (Box 114)
    - "A Hermaphrodite God", 1987, undated (Box 114)
    - Miscellaneous articles, undated (Box 114)
    - "Limited Edition Club", undated (Box 114)
    - "Intro to Hunting Stories", 1988, undated (Box 114)
    - Percy, Walker, 1991 (Box 114)
    - "Texas A&M Lecture", 1988 (Box 114)
    - Lecture material (Texas A&M, New Mexico), undated (Box 114)
    - "'The Role of the Humanities in the Technological Age' New Mexico Military Institute 4/12/88", undated (Box 114)
    - "The True Use of the Humanities", undated (Box 114)
    - "Faulkner Lecture Pastoral and the Historic", 1987, undated (Box 114)
    - "Proof from Japan", undated (Box 114)
    - "Linguistics Either Buick Lectures or LAS", undated (Box 114)
    - "The Past Alive in the Present", undated (Box 114)
    - Brown, Larry, undated (Box 114)
    - "J. C. Ransom", 1987, undated (Box 114)
    - "40 Years of Understanding Poetry", undated (Box 114)
    - Notes for articles, undated (Box 114)
    - "Walker Percy", undated (Box 114)
    - "A CAO in London in the '60s", 1988, undated (Box 114)
    - "Cultural Affairs Officer (1988)", 1988, undated (Box 114)
    - " The Wasteland: 60 Years After - Notes and Early Drafts August 1988", 1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 114)
    - "Tink's Letters to K. A. P.", 1937-1972; 3 folders (Box 115)
    - "K. A. P. Letters", 1938-1993 (Box 115)
    - "My Letters to K. A. P.", 1942-1975 (Box 115)
    - "Names of Those Sent Card and/or Letter About I", 1986, undated (Box 115)
    - "Katherine Anne Porter Conference U. of Maryland May 91", 1990-1991 (Box 115)
    - "Trip to England 6 Mar - 23 March 1992", 1992, undated (Box 115)
    - "London - Trip in Feb.", 1994, undated (Box 115)
    - "Materials on My Life for Tenn. Human. Council", 1984-1985 (Box 115)
    - Articles and reviews on Faulkner, 1932-1936, undated (Box 115)
    - "The Past Alive in the Present", undated (Box 115)
    - "Lectures 1987 Welty", 1985-1987, undated (Box 115)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988, undated (Box 115)
    - " As I Lay Dying Bruccoli", 1988, undated (Box 115)
    - "Washington", 1983-1985 (Box 115)
    - On the Prejudices, Predilections, and Firm Beliefs of Wm Faulkner, setting copy, 1988; 2 folders (Box 115)
    - "VIII 17th Century Book, Xerox Materials", 1985-1986, undated (Box 115)
    - Arizona State University, 1983 (Box 115)
    - "Modern Rhetoric Active File 1983", 1983, undated (Box 115)
    - "Tenn. Humanities Council", 1987-1989, undated (Box 115)
    - University of South Carolina, 1989-1990 (Box 115)
    - "Brooks Family in the West", 1987-1989 (Box 115)
    - "Sweetbriar College April 16, 1980", 1983, undated (Box 115)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine, printed issue, 1990 (Box 115)
    - "Red W's Essay on Me & Eliot Material", 1937-1985, undated (Box 115)
    - Newsletters, 1990-1993 (Box 115)
    - "R. P. Warren Conference, New Haven Aug. 8-9, 1987 Letters", 2 folders (Box 115)
    - "All the King's Men (Levy Lectures)", 1988, undated (Box 115)
    - Articles on Warren and Faulkner, 1986-1992, undated (Box 115)
    - Miscellaneous articles and notes, 1993, undated (Box 115)
    - "Foreword to Warren Collection", undated (Box 115)
    - "Warren", 1977-1994, undated (Box 116)
    - Grimshaw, 1991 (Box 116)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and notes, 1989-1990, undated (Box 116)
    - "Atlanta Trip 12 Oct. 1993", 1993, undated (Box 116)
    - "Warren Lecture Quotations, Time, Nature, Reality, Etc.", undated (Box 116)
    - "Center for R. P. Warren Studies", 1985-1992, undated (Box 116)
    - "Foreword (xerox) Warren Collection Austin Peay", undated (Box 116)
    - "East Texas on Warren", undated (Box 116)
    - "Tulane Course - Crisis in Culture," notebook, 1976 (Box 116)
    - "Faulkner Course 1973," notebook (Box 116)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1987-1992, undated (Box 116)
    - Empty folders, undated; 6 folders (Box 116)
    - "KAP - Tinkham Letters," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - Faulkner notebooks, 1979, undated (Box 116)
    - "W. B. Yeats," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - "Guild of Southern Writers", 1981-1993, undated (Box 116)
    - "Projects & Ideas," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - "Notebook Left by C. and E. B. Brooks for the Berkeley Theological Conference 1961," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - "File of Holdings 1982," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - "M. Montgomery", 1986-1992, undated (Box 116)
    - "Faulkner Conference Programs + Publicity", 1984-1990 (Box 116)
    - "Miss. Conversation on Narrative", 1988, undated (Box 116)
    - "Faulkner Notes," notebook, 1986-1987 (Box 116)
    - "Brook - Wimsatt Book," notebook, undated (Box 116)
    - "Finder," notebook, 1986 (Box 117)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 117)
    - "Important Permission to Print K. A. P. - Letters", 1994 (Box 117)
    - "Miss Emerson's Copy", 1964-1989 (Box 117)
    - "Letters to Answer Late Nov. 1990", 1965 (Box 117)
    - "Copies of Letters Jan - Feb 1988", 1961-1966 (Box 117)
    - "K. A. Porter Letters to E. B. Brooks (Transcript of a selection)", 1940-1993 (Box 117)
    - "K. A. P. Letters/Notes on Omissions and Cuts" (empty folder), undated (Box 117)
    - On the Prejudices, Predilections, and Firm Beliefs of William Faulkner, 1987 (Box 117)
    - "Faulkner Bibliography", 1970-1971 (Box 117)
    - "Miscellaneous Faulkner Material - Letters, Notes, etc.", 1971-1985, undated (Box 117)
    - "'English' and the Perils of Formalism", undated (Box 117)
    - "Center for Study of Southern Culture", 1984-1985, undated (Box 117)
    - "Eliot Meeting St. Louis", 1987-1988 (Box 117)
    - "Nashville Tenn. Festival", 1987, undated (Box 117)
    - "Faulkner Newsletter", 1981-1984 (Box 117)
    - "Texas A&M", 1987-1988 (Box 117)
    - "Tocqueville Lecture", undated (Box 117)
    - Fellowship of Southern Writers, 1986-1993, undated; 7 folders (Box 117)
    - Miscellaneous educational material, 1963-1988, undated (Box 117)
    - "Penny's Notes", 1986-1987, undated (Box 117)
    - Center for Robert Penn Warren Studies, 1990-1994, undated (Box 117)
    - "The Evolution of English", 1949-1974, undated (Box 117)
    - "Risen from the Bloody Sod: Recovering from Southern Tradition", 1991; 2 folders (Box 117)
    - "Cumberland Poetry Review" (empty envelope), 1992 May 27 (Box 117)
    - "Yale College Introductory Information," printed version, 1988 July 20 (Box 117)
    - Newspapers clippings on Faulkner, 1972-1982, undated (Box 117)
    - Miscellaneous Faulkner material, 1953-1993 (Box 117)
    - Brooks on Faulkner, 1978-1991, undated (Box 117)
    - "Faulkner Themes To Be Explored", 1986, undated (Box 117)
    - "Against the Newest Criticism Brooks, Peyre, et. al.", 1979-1982, undated (Box 118)
    - "Columbia Lecture 15 Oct. '82", 1982, undated (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous notes and articles, 1957-1983, undated; 2 folders (Box 118)
    - "To His Coy Mistress & the Garden - Earlier Drafts", 1982, undated (Box 118)
    - "Herbert Notes and Scattered Comments", 1967, undated (Box 118)
    - "Notes for Final Chapter - Hudibras", 1958-1960, undated (Box 118)
    - "The Grasshopper", 1959, undated (Box 118)
    - "Carew", undated (Box 118)
    - "Corbett - Notes and Obsolete Copy", undated (Box 118)
    - "The Exequy - Notes and Extra Copies", 1980, undated (Box 118)
    - "Shirley - Death the Leveler. Notes", 1982, undated (Box 118)
    - "Daniel", undated (Box 118)
    - "Fanshawe Notes", undated (Box 118)
    - "Horatian Ode Final Draft", undated (Box 118)
    - "Corbett", undated (Box 118)
    - Marvell; Clark, undated (Box 118)
    - "17th Century Poets," notebook, undated (Box 118)
    - "Discussions of Marvell (To Be Kept for Your New History-Criticism Project)", 1972, undated (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1971, undated; 2 folders (Box 118)
    - "Bibliography for WWU (Subsequent Essays)", undated (Box 118)
    - "Puritanism 17th Cent.", undated (Box 118)
    - "Marvell's Religious Poetry", undated (Box 118)
    - "17th Century Texts" (empty folder), undated (Box 118)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1994, undated; 9 folders (Box 118)
    - "Poetic Traditions of the English Renaissance," offprint, 1982 (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1960, undated (Box 118)
    - Modern Maturity, printed version, 1992 (Box 118)
    - "Song of Songs / Sussex Dialect", undated (Box 118)
    - "Hubbell Medal", 1978-1979 (Box 119)
    - "Lamar Lectures (Mercer U.) (Oct. 22-23, 1984)", 1984, undated; 2 folders (Box 119)
    - Correspondence, 1965, undated (Box 119)
    - "Letters from Tinkum to Cleanth", 1929-1931 (Box 119)
    - "Personal Career", 1965-1983, undated (Box 119)
    - Photo of Cleanth and Tinkum, circa 1930s (Box 119)
    - "Tink's Letters", 1966-1975, undated (Box 119)
    - "Personal (Non-Archival)", 1965-1985, undated (Box 119)
    - "K. A. P. Material Current 16 May, 1992", 1991-1992 (Box 119)
    - "Personal File (Misc.) May, 1981", 1986, undated (Box 119)
    - "New Mexico Military Institute 1987," photo album (Box 119)
    - "Lamar III Final Texts", undated (Box 119)
    - "Warren Commemorative Writings by C. B.", undated (Box 119)
    - "The Rest of the Language Lecture", undated (Box 119)
    - "Homage to R. P. Warren", undated (Box 119)
    - "Warren Reminiscence", 1980-1991, undated (Box 119)
    - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, undated (Box 119)
    - "Warren Lecture", undated (Box 119)
    - Miscellaneous Warren material, 1985-1990 (Box 119)
    - Newspaper clippings on Robert Penn Warren, 1985-1986, undated (Box 119)
    - "The Mad Druggist", undated (Box 119)
    - "St. Louis Eliot Conference Book", undated (Box 119)
    - Keys to the city, 1991, undated (Box 119)
    - "The Cleanth Brooks Collection at the University of Southern Mississippi - A Finding List", 1991 (Box 119)
    - "Song of Songs / Sussex Dialect," audiocassette, undated (Box 120)
    - Brodsky, Louis Daniel, 1988 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Proof From Japan", undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Washington", 1983-1985 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - Articles on Warren and Faulkner, 1986-1992, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Faulkner Conference Programs + Publicity", 1984-1990 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Miscellaneous Faulkner Material - Letters, Notes, etc.", 1971-1985, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Faulkner Newsletter", 1981-1984 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - Fellowship of Southern Writers, 1988-1993 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Penny's Notes", 1986-1987, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "The Evolution of English", 1949-1974, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - Clippings on Faulkner, 1972-1982, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous Faulkner material, 1953-1993 (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Notes for Final Chapter - Hudibras", 1958-1960, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Personal Career", 1965-1983, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - "Personal (Non-Archival)", 1965-1985, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous Warren material, 1985-1990 (Box 121 (Oversize))
  - January 1995 Acquisition, 5.25' (6 boxes)
    Gift of the estate of Cleanth Brooks.
    Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 422.
    - Outgoing correspondence (copies), 1988-1994; 9 folders (Box 122)
    - Index of authors, undated (Box 122)
    - Harvard New Books, 1993 (Box 122)
    - Historical Evidence and Poetry, undated; 3 folders (Box 122)
    - Pinkerton - Percy, undated (Box 122)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1983, undated (Box 122)
    - Newspaper clippings and writings, undated (Box 122)
    - "To Sing the Truth: The Poetry of Davidson's Later Years", undated (Box 122)
    - Toward Yoknapatapha, corrected proofs, 1977, undated (Box 123)
    - "Mlle. de Maupin & Other Early Influences", undated (Box 123)
    - "British Reviews of Faulkner", 1933-1935, undated (Box 123)
    - "Theology", 1965, undated (Box 123)
    - Cobb, Irving, undated (Box 123)
    - "Maybe of Interest for Biblio", 1985 (Box 123)
    - "Reviews of Toward Yoknapatawpha ", 1978-1985, undated (Box 123)